Cecily Rowland

A full-stack developer with experience in Ruby and Javascript, including React. A curious and inquisitive Makers Graduate with a love for learning and for building useful things. A former Public Relations professional with an extensive background in collaborative teamwork, and impeccable EQ skills.

London 07565294110 cec1rowland@gmail.com Github LinkedIn

EXPERIENCE

Makers Academy Student

NOV 2022 - FEB 2023

- Learned the **fundamental principles** of software engineering, such as OOP and TDD, as well as Agile and XP methodologies.
- Worked in a broad range of languages and frameworks such as Ruby,
 Sinatra, Javascript, React, Express, MongoDB and PostgreSQL.
- **Successfully collaborated with other learners** to identify realistic MVP's and deliver them to deadlines.

Tate Modern — Visitor's Experience Assistant

JUNE 2021 - PRESENT

- Acted as the first point of contact for visitors to the Tate Modern, communicating key information about the gallery to members of the public.
- Facilitated and contributed to talks and tours on the gallery floor.
- Identified deficiencies in the running of the gallery, flagging them to management and bringing about key changes to the visitors' experience.

LUCHFORD — Senior Account Executive

SEPT 2019 - MAY 2020

- **Strategised and pulled together yearly PR plans**, analysing relevant data and outlining every aspect of clients' press activity.
- Crisis management and client liaison: responded to press and worked with the client in the face of adversity and industry turmoil.
- Produced blog content and press releases around client activity and campaigns.

Grayling Communications — Account Executive

AUG 2018 - SEPT 2019

- **Relationship building** with members of the press to secure national media coverage.
- Managed and coordinated agencies in different markets around the world.
- **Prioritised workload** within strict time frames

EDUCATION:

University of Kent — First Class Honours in History of Art 2013 - 20

PROJECTS

Endangered Species Map *React, Sinatra*

Acebook MERN stack

Workout Buddy MERN stack

Makers BnBPostgreSQL, Ruby, HTML

Birthday Calculator *Ruby, HTML*

Dojo Blog React

VOULUNTEERING

Celia Hammond Animal Trust 2010 - 2019

INTERNSHIPS

Rostrum PR - 2017

Somesuch Production - 2014

The Times - 2010

INTERESTS

Knitting (all wool crafts!)

Writing: Songwriting, creative nonfiction

Reading

Yoga and weight training

Jigsaws